And on that point, members of the jury...
陪审团 ，就以这一点...
I rest my case.
我的报告到此为止
Hello, Wanda.
万达，你好
- Hi, Ken. - Hello, Wanda.
- 肯，你好 - 你好，万达
Ken, this is Otto.
肯，这是奥图
Hello, Ken. Wanda's told me a lot about you.
你好，肯，万达常提起你的
Hey, great fish!
很棒的鱼
A little squeeze of lemon, some tartar sauce, perfect.
加一点柠檬水，酸泡菜调味酱 棒极了
George back yet?
乔治回来了没有？
No, he had to go to--
没有，他要去...
What?
什么？
That's quite a stutter you've got there, Ken.
你口吃的相当厉害，肯
It doesn't bother me.
我不介意
So George needs a weapons man, eh?
乔治需要懂得用武器的人？
A cup of tea, Ken?
肯，要茶吗？
Yeah, he'd like one.
他会想要的
I had a good friend in the C.I.A. had a stutter.
我在中央情报局的一位朋友 也有口吃
It cost him his life, damn it.
这要了他的命，可恶
Hi, George.
乔治，你好
Hello, George. Get you a scotch?
乔治，你好，你要威士忌吗？
Yeah.
好的
This is Otto.
这是奥图
- You're Wanda's brother. - It's good to be here, George.
- 你是万达的哥哥 - 乔治，我很高兴来到这里
England is a fine country.
英国是个很好的国家
She tell you what we need?
她告诉了你我们需要什么吗？
Something like that?
类似这些？
Something like that.
类似这些
Hello, Wendy.
温迪，你好
Had a good day?
今天怎样？
I spent the morning trying to get the waste disposal man to come...
我整个早上都在 叫垃圾处理人员来这里
have lunch with Majorie Brooks who complained about her husband...
我和玛杰莉布克吃午饭 她不断地埋怨丈夫
then I had to play three rubbers with Philippa Hunter...
然后我和菲利帕玩游戏
and I come back here and Sanderson's have sent the wrong flowers.
然后我回来这里 桑特森送错花了
Oh, no.
哎呀，真糟糕
- Would you like some tea? - Yes.
- 你想喝茶吗？ - 好的
I won the case.
我赢了官司
This is the first moment I've had to myself all day.
我现在才拥有一些私人时刻
Hello, Portia. How was the show?
你好，波席亚，表演怎样？
Awful, Daddy. I need a new horse.
很糟，爸爸，我需要一匹新马
- I thought you liked Phantom. - He's not fit for dog meat.
- 我以为你喜欢“魅影” - 它不适合我
Can I change him please, Dad? It's vital and won't cost much.
我可以换掉它吗？ 很重要的，而且不需要很多钱
- We ought to ask Belinda. - I thought you were making tea.
- 我们要问贝琳达 - 我以为你在泡茶
- I am, darling. Sorry. - Suppose I'd better get it.
- 我是，对不起 - 我去弄吧
- Let me do it, please. - No, I'll do it.
- 让我来 - 不，让我来
- I won the case. - Now this is cracked.
- 我赢了官司 - 这个裂了
They're worth about 1 00,000 each. There are 1 35 of them.
它们每个值十万元 总共有135个
That makes 1 3 million, my friends.
也就是一千三百万
- Dollars or pounds? - Pounds, pet.
- 美金还是英镑？ - 是英镑
This is the big one.
这是大买卖
Okay.
好
Yeah.
对
- Otto? - Yes?
- 奥图？ - 什么事？
Okay?
行吗？
- What? - The plan.
- 什么？ - 计划
Yeah, great. No problem.
对，没问题
What was the middle thing about the police?
关于应付警方方面怎样？
We don't meet up at Heathrow until Tuesday--
我们周二在希思罗机场会合
- Oh, yeah. - I haven't finished yet.
- 对 - 我还没说完
Because the police will watch all the airports...
因为警方会监视所有机场...
for 72 hours.
持续72小时监视
I know.
我知道
You want me to...
你想不想我...
get a big...
找一辆大汽车...
car for the getaway?
准备作逃亡之用？
Yes, Ken. A limo, okay?
肯，找来一辆轿车，好吗？
And put diplomatic plates on it, right?
在上面挂上外交车牌，好吗？
What if he has to say something during the break-in?
如他在抢劫期间要说话怎办？
Nobody says anything during the break-in, Otto.
没有人会在抢劫期间说话
It's okay, Otto. Ken's good.
奥图 ，没关系，肯没问题的
So, next week...
那么下周...
we won't have to look for work...
我们不用找工作
and it won't have to look for us.
它也不用找我们
Oscar Wilde.
奥斯卡怀尔德
You really like animals, don't you, Ken?
肯，你很喜欢动物吧？
What's the attraction?
它们有什么吸引你？
Because you can trust them...
因为你能够信任它们
and they don't sh--
它们不会...
- Shit on you? - Show off all the time.
- 在你身上撒尿？ - 不会经常炫耀
You know what Nietzsche said about them?
你知道尼采怎样形容它们吗？
He said they were God's second blunder.
他说它们是天主的第二个错误
Bye, sis.
再见，妹妹
Well, you tell him from me...
你帮我告诉他...
that I could show you--
我可以给你看...
Bye, George.
乔治，再见
If you talk to Mom, tell her I said hi.
如果你见到母亲，替我问候她
- Don't let him touch you. - One more day, we're together.
- 不要让他碰你 - 再过一天我们就能在一起了
I'm sorry about my brother. I know he's insensitive.
我为我的哥哥道歉 我知道他很麻木不仁
He's had a hard life. Dad used to beat him up.
他的生活很苦，爸爸以前常打他
Good.
好
Anybody moves, and you're dead!
不许动，否则你们死定了
Look where you're going, chauvinist pig.
笨蛋，小心走路
Really, people here just think they own the pavement.
这里的人以为他们拥有行人道
That was fun. I love robbing the English.
真有趣，我喜欢抢劫英国人
They're so polite.
他们很有礼貌
- What is it, Ken? - The dog.
- 肯，什么事？ - 那条狗
We didn't hit the dog.
我们没有撞到那条狗
Twenty million dollars, he's worried about an insect.
这关乎二千万元 他竟然担心一条虫
- It's not an in-- - Stutter's not getting any better.
- 这不是... - 你的口吃没有改善
- Have you thought about surgery? - Shut up.
- 你有没有想过做手术？ - 住口
Bye.
再见
- Let's split. - Meet you at Heathrow on Tuesday.
- 我们分道扬镳吧 - 周二在希思罗机场见
Lie low. No celebrating.
低调点，不准庆祝
No celebrating?
不准庆祝？
- See you in a couple of hours. - Okay. Bye.
- 两小时后见 - 好，再见
- To 20 million. - To a job well done.
- 为二千万元干杯 - 为大功告成干杯
To us.
为我们干杯
To the best brother and sister team since--
继罗密欧与茱丽叶后...
Romeo and Juliet? Yeah.
最佳的兄妹队伍干杯？好极了
Do you believe those Cockney klutzes bought our story? What morons!
你相信那些蠢才信了我们吗？ 真是笨蛋！
- I want you to know something. - What?
- 我想告诉你一件事 - 什么事？
Even if you were my brother, I'd still want to fuck you.
就算你是我的哥哥 我仍然想和你上床
Make the call.
打电话
No Italian!
不准说意大利话
Make the call, Otto.
奥图 ，打电话
Are you really Italian?
你真的是意大利人吗？
My name is Otto. It means ''eight.'' Say ''Arrivederci a Georgio. ''
我叫奥图 ， “八” 的意思 说“乔治，再见”吧
- Good-bye, George. - Can you put me through to the police?
- 乔治，再见 - 可以帮我接警局吗？
Yes, hello. Sorry to trouble you.
你好，抱歉打扰你
I thought it might interest you to know the Hatton Garden robbery...
你们应该有兴趣知道 哈顿花园的抢劫
was pulled off by a Mr. George Thomason...
是由一位乔治汤玛森先生策划的
who lives at Flat Three...
他住在西伦敦
Kipling Mansions, Murray Road...
梅利路基普利公寓
London West Nine.
三号
Police. Open up.
警察，开门
Come on. Open up.
开门
Open the door, or we'll knock it down.
开门，否则我们会撞开这道门
George Francis Thomason.
乔治法兰西汤玛森
Passport? Tickets?
护照？机票？
Money.
钱
Asshole!
混蛋
- We're rich, Wanda. - Yup.
- 万达，我们很有钱 - 对
Bet these last weeks with me were the most exciting weeks of your life.
和我在一起过去这两个礼拜 是你生命里最刺激的时刻
You said it.
你说得对
Okay.
好
Disappointed!
真失望！
Son of a bitch!
混蛋
What do you have to do in this life to make people trust you?
你这辈子要做什么 才会令人相信你？
Shut up.
住口
- People always take advantage of me. - Shut up and think.
- 人们总是利用我 - 住口然后想想吧
Where has he moved it?
他把它移到哪里？
- What are you doing? - I'm thinking.
- 你在做什么？ - 我在思考
I'm thinking of what I'm going to do to him.
我在想我要怎样对付他
First I'll hang him up with piano wire. Where are you going?
首先我会用琴线勒死他 你去哪里？
I'm going to talk to him.
我去和他谈谈
Talk to who?
跟谁谈？
In the course of installing these windows for your parents...
在你为父母安装窗门期间
you knelt on the floor where there was broken glass from a dropped pane.
你跪在破碎窗户地上的 玻璃碎片上
That's right.
对
Your mother and father can confirm this?
你的父母可以证实吗？
Yes, and his aunt, Georgina Thomason.
可以 还有他的婶婶乔治亚汤玛森
Good, Bartlett. Yes?
巴勒，是的？
Sorry to interrupt you, sir. Thomason, young lady to see you.
抱歉打扰你，有位小姐来见你
- Anything else? - That's everything for the moment.
- 还有什么事？ - 暂时没有
- You don't have to dash off? - No, absolutely not.
- 你不用赶着离开吗？ - 不用
George, Ken's got the fish food.
乔治，肯买了鱼食
- He'll be in later. - Thanks.
- 他晚点回来 - 谢谢你
- What do you think, Mr. Leach? - We may be all right with the glass.
- 利奇先生，你认为怎样？ - 玻璃的事没问题
What else are they gonna come up with?
他们还会做什么？
Oh, my God. I can't believe this is happening.
我的天，我不相信会发生这种事
That's not allowed in here, miss.
小姐，这里不容许这样
- Are you okay? - I'm all right.
- 你有没有事？ - 我没事
George, I don't think I can handle this.
乔治，我认为我不能应付
I was so afraid to sleep last night. I thought the police were coming.
昨晚我害怕得不能入睡 我以为警察会来
Leave it out, okay?
别提了 ，好吗？
Listen, listen.
听着...
You stayed at my place.
你在我那里住
We slept late. You made me breakfast.
我们很晚才睡，你弄早饭给我吃
What?
什么？
What's he doing here?
他在这里做什么？
He wanted to see you.
他想见你
Who did it, George? Kevin Delaney?
乔治，是谁做的？凯文迪兰尼？
You want me to rub him out? Anything. You name it.
你想我干掉他吗？ 你想我做什么就说吧
- I have friends making inquiries. - Good.
- 我有朋友帮我查探 - 好
The jewels are very safe.
珠宝很安全
If I get sent down, it all gets handed back to cut my sentence.
如果我被捕 我会归还所有珠宝来减轻刑期
Now, to cut my sentence even more...
为了再减少刑期...
I could tell them who done it with me...
我可以告诉他们谁是我的搭档
if I wasn't very happy about everything.
如果我有任何事不满意的话
What was the middle thing?
你刚才说什么？
Piss off.
滚开
- Do you want me to-- - Now.
- 你想不想我... - 马上
- You don't think-- - Do you?
- 你不认为... - 你认为吗？
- George? - What?
- 乔治？ - 什么？
Are you sure the garage is very safe?
你肯定车库安全吗？
Trust me.
相信我
Thank you very much.
谢谢你
Thanks a lot. Bye. Have a good day.
谢谢你，再见
- So? - He's not sure it was you.
- 那又怎样？ - 他不肯定是你
- That's something, I guess. - What about you?
- 那样不错 - 你又怎样？
He believes me. That's why he can't figure out about you.
他相信我，所以他对你不肯定
- Figure out what? - If you turned him in or not, stupid.
- 他对什么不肯定？ - 他不肯定是否你供出他，笨蛋
Don't...
千万...
ever, ever...
不要...
call me stupid, okay?
叫我笨蛋，知道吗？
What?
什么？
That's George's lawyer.
那是乔治的律师
The other guy must be the barrister.
另一个一定是大律师
- So? - Trust me.
- 那又怎样？ - 相信我
You let me know if anything unexpected turns up.
若发生什么意料之外的事 记得通知我
Excuse me.
对不起
Don't I recognize you?
我是不是认识你的？
No, I don't think so.
应该不认识
But you are a famous barrister, aren't you?
但你是有名的大律师吧？
Well, hardly.
不算是
Could I have your autograph anyway?
可不可以帮我签名？
- Yes, certainly. - Thanks.
- 当然可以 - 谢谢你
I'm studying aspects of your legal system.
我在研究你们的法制
- I'm American. - Oh, really?
- 我是美国人 - 真的？
I've only just started, though. It's fascinating.
我只是刚开始研究 我觉得很有趣
What brings you here?
你为什么来这里？
It's a little embarrassing.
说起来会令人有点尴尬
I have a friend.
我有一位朋友
Oh, I see. Well, there you are.
我明白了 ，好了
I knew it! You're Archie Leash!
我早就知道！你是阿奇利许！
- Leach. - Right.
- 利奇 - 对
I saw you in court two weeks ago.
两周前我在法庭上见过你
- The casino break-in? - You were great!
- 赌场被劫事件？ - 你很棒
- Well. - I'm a big fan of yours.
- 我... - 我很仰慕你
I love the way you cross-examine.
我喜欢你的盘问技巧
I really admire your work.
我真的很佩服你
Thank you.
谢谢
- I'd better not keep you. - I don't suppose you-- Fine. Right.
- 我不会再打扰你 - 我不...没关系
Well.
好
Thank you for this. I'll treasure it.
谢谢你，我会很珍惜
You speak French too.
你也会说法文
What's going on?
发生什么事？
Whatever George decides to do, he's going to tell Leach first.
不管乔治决定做什么 他会先告诉利奇
- Why? - 'Cause he's his lawyer.
- 为什么？ - 因为他是乔治的律师
- Yeah, I know that. - So I'm gonna get to know Mr. Leach.
- 我知道 - 我会去认识利奇先生
'Cause George is gonna tell him where the diamonds are.
因为乔治会告诉他钻石在哪里
That's what I'm gonna find out.
那是我要查出的事
You've done well, my son.
你做得很好
Now, where are we going to hide it?
我们要把它藏在哪里？
Very good. Don't tell Wanda anything.
很好，不要告诉万达
Otto might get something out of her.
奥图或许会问她
George, you are gonna get off?
乔治，你会没事吧？
Sure, don't worry about it, Ken. We'll fix it.
对，肯，不用担心，我们会处理
Now, anything on Otto?
对奥图有什么发现吗？
- Not yet. - You watch him.
- 还没有 - 你监视着他
It's okay.
没问题
Looks like the police have been all over it.
看来警察们搜查过所有东西
Let me just change clothes, then I'll help you look.
让我先更衣，然后我帮你找
Hello, Ken's pets.
你好，肯的宠物
Wake up, limey fish!
英国鱼，醒来！
So, how are you gonna get friendly with this lawyer?
你怎样去认识这个律师？
I don't know. I'll improvise.
我不知道，我会随机应变
Fucking insects!
可恶的昆虫！
I thought Englishmen didn't like women, the way they talk.
从他们说话的态度来看 我以为英国人不喜欢女人
He's straight. He's kind of cute, in a pompous sort of way.
他很直接，他其实蛮可爱
You got the hots for him?
你喜欢他吗？
I'm not into necrophilia. Thanks.
我没有恋尸癖，谢谢
What is this? Hump-a-limey week, suddenly?
这是什么一回事？ 突然变了 “引诱英国人周”吗？
Otto doesn't approve. Otto might get jealous.
奥图不喜欢，他或许会妒忌
Oh, speak it!
说出来吧！
Yeah.
对
No, not here, Otto.
奥图 ，不要在这里
No, not here,
不，不要在这里
Otto. No,
奥图 ，不！
Look what I've got, Wanda.
万达，看我有什么
A treasure.
宝藏
Oh, my God, Ken, it's you. I thought it was the police again.
我的天，是肯，我以为又是警方
Isn't it horrible about George? Oh, Ken!
乔治还真可怜呢？ 噢，肯
I have such a bad headache. Could you run and get me some aspirin?
肯，我头痛 你可以帮我买些阿斯匹灵吗？
- Shit. - What's that?
- 糟了 - 那是什么？
That's my brother. He's in the bathroom.
我哥哥在浴室里
We just saw George. Oh, it was horrible, Ken.
我们刚见过乔治，实在好可怕
Just horrible.
真的很可怕
Isn't it terrible about George?
乔治很可怜吧？
When I find the bastard who squealed--
如果让我找到那个告密者...
I love that man!
我喜欢他！
What are you doing here?
你在做什么？
What am I doing here?
我在做什么？
Wanda was upset, Ken. She needed to talk to family.
万达很不高兴 她需要和家人谈谈
She's just had a shower.
她刚洗完澡
I've got to speak to you.
我要和你谈谈
- Are you okay now? - I'm fine. Thanks for coming.
- 你现在没事吧？ - 我没事，谢谢你来
- Call me if you need me again. - Okay. Thanks.
- 需要我就打电话给我 - 好，谢谢你
What's the matter with you? Can't you think about her feelings?
你怎么了？ 你不能考虑她的感受吗？
- There's something funny going on. - Oh, dear.
- 事情很可疑 - 糟了
You don't even know why you're excited, do you?
你连自己为什么兴奋也不知道 是吗？
I didn't want to say anything while George was around.
我不想乔治在场时说话
Isn't it time you faced up to certain realities?
你是时候面对现实了吧？
Come on. You're a very attractive man.
你是个很有吸引力的男人
You're smart, you've got wonderful bones...
你很聪明，有很棒的骨架
great eyes and you dress really interestingly.
很漂亮的眼睛，衣着有趣
We could have a lot of fun together, you and I.
我们一起一定会很高兴 就是你跟我
We'd be really good for each other. What do you say?
我们会很适合对方 你认为怎样？
You must be jo--
你一定是在说笑...
- May I kiss you, Ken? - No, you fucking can't!
- 肯，我可以吻你吗？ - 不可以
Just a peck. No tongue. Ken!
只是轻轻一吻 但不是湿吻
You didn't realize I was gay.
你不知道我是同性恋
Okay, look, I'm sorry.
对不起
I've handled this badly.
我处理得很糟
Look, the physical side can wait.
肉体可以等待
You need time.
你需要时间
Will you think about it?
你会考虑吗？
Oh, my God.
我的天
Ken, somebody just called!
肯，有人打过电话来
They said the police know the loot is in a garage in Fulham somewhere.
他们说警方知道赃货 在福汉的一个车库里
You and I have to go get it right now.
我们要立即去拿它
You and I have to go before the police find out where it is.
我们要比警方先一步找出地点
- What? - It's all right.
- 什么？ - 没事
What?
什么？
George.
乔治
Moved.
移走了它
- George moved the loot? - Yes.
- 乔治移走了赃货？ - 对
Where did he move it, Ken?
肯，他移去了哪里？
I don't know where it is. There's a key. I don't know what it's for.
我不知道，有钥匙 但不知道用来开什么
It's in the--
是在...
Don't tell me. It's better that you don't tell me.
不要告诉我 你还是不要告诉我
Oh, you know, if it wasn't for George.
如果不是为了乔治
Otto...
奥图...
tried to kiss me.
尝试吻我
I thought he might.
我认为他或许会
No. Nothing. No marks at all.
什么都没有，没有痕迹
- But it is a safety deposit box key? - Oh, yes.
- 但这是保险箱钥匙吧？ - 对
But it could be any one in England. There are millions of them.
但英国有数以百万计的保险箱
Hotels, banks, offices. Sorry.
饭店、银行、办公室...对不起
Thank you.
谢谢你
Fuck.
可恶
That's him, Inspector.
警官，就是他
He's the one who tried to murder my dogs.
是他想谋杀我的狗儿们
Davidson?
大卫森？
There's an American legal student here who wants to see me for a moment.
有位美国法律学生想和我谈谈
- What time's Sir John due? - Half past 1 2:00, sir.
- 约翰爵士什么时候来？ - 十二点半
Come in.
进来
- Hi. - How very nice to see you.
- 你好 - 幸会
- Am I interrupting? - Absolutely not.
- 我有打扰你吗？ - 当然不是
- Really? - Really. Delighted to see you.
- 真的？ - 真的，很高兴能和你见面
Hello.
你好
So, this is the place, huh?
就是这里？
- This is it. - Very nice.
- 对 - 很不错
I was over at the courts this morning. Boy, it's fascinating.
今早我去过法庭 实在很引人入胜
- Really so much to know. - You like it?
- 我可以学到很多东西 - 你喜欢吗？
Everybody wears these. Do you wear one?
大家都戴这个，你也戴吗？
Ridiculous.
荒谬
Well, I only have a few minutes before-- Sorry.
我只有几分钟时间...对不起
- I'm sorry. - Till then I'm all yours, as they say.
- 对不起 - 我现在洗耳恭听
I just have a couple of questions.
我只有几个问题
I'm having a little problem understanding...
我对于初步刑事程序...
- preliminary criminal procedures. - Good.
- 不大明白 - 很好
What exactly is the committal?
什么是监听会？
Ah, interesting.
很有趣
Basically, it's a preliminary investigation...
基本上是初步调查
where the prosecution presents prima facie evidence...
控方提出初步证据
that the accused has a case to answer for trial.
证明有足够证据向被告提出起诉
That's what the books say.
书本是那样写的
Let's just take, for example, my friend George Thomason.
例如我的朋友乔治汤玛森
- Right. - When he goes into his committal--
- 对 - 当他被...
- Thomason? - Yes.
- 汤玛森？ - 对
Do you know him?
你认识他吗？
- I'm defending him. - What are you talking about?
- 我在为他辩护 - 你在说什么？
I'm his barrister, his lawyer.
我是他的代表律师
That's so great.
真棒
That's so weird. Isn't that weird?
真古怪，你觉得很古怪吧？
I'm so happy it's you that's defending him.
我很高兴你帮他辩护
Thank you.
谢谢
He's sure to get off now.
他一定能够脱罪
Wow.
难以置信
- I could watch you work now. - Please.
- 我现在可以看你工作 - 谢谢
Amazing.
真了不起
Anyway, at the committal, George would then plead--
乔治会在监听会...
- Not guilty. - Really?
- 不认罪 - 真的？
Oh, you see, the evidence against him is largely circumstantial.
他们的证据大部分是间接证据
But there was an identification, wasn't there?
但是有目击证人吧？
True, but a very elderly lady. I think they've got the wrong man.
但那是一个老妇人 我认为他们抓错人
You don't think he did it.
你认为不是他做的
Let's just say, for argument's sake, that you did think he did it.
为了讨论，假设你认为是他做的
If further evidence against him came to light, for example.
如果还有对他不利的证据
You would then advise him to plead guilty...
你会建议他认罪
and turn over the jewels to get his sentence cut.
归还珠宝以求减刑
And he would turn them over to who? To you?
他会把珠宝交给谁？你？
- Theoretically? - Oh, of course.
- 理论上可以这样说 - 当然
Well, uh--
这样...
I'm so sorry. I've forgotten your name.
抱歉我忘了你的名字
Wonderful, wonderful. Wanda, there were really three--
万达，真棒...真的有三个...
- Not Wanda Gershwitz? - Yes.
- 你不是万达格肖维吧？ - 我是
Oh, my God.
我的天
- What? - You're his alibi.
- 什么事？ - 你是他的不在场证据
- I can't talk to you. - Why not?
- 我不能和你谈 - 为什么？
My dear young lady, you are a defense witness.
小姐，你是辩方证人
I must ask you to leave immediately. I'm so sorry.
我要立即请你离开，对不起
What did I say?
我说过什么？
- It's not ethical to talk to a witness. - Everybody does it in America.
- 和证人谈话是不合道德的 - 在美国是可以的
Well, not in England. It's strictly forbidden.
在英国是绝对禁止这样做
I must insist, otherwise I may have to give up the case.
我要坚持这样 否则我要放弃这宗案件
I'm sorry. Please?
对不起，请离开？
I didn't come here today to talk about boring criminal procedures.
我今天不是来谈刑事程序
Come on. You know.
你是知道的
You knew the minute I walked in here.
我进来的那一刻你已经知道
I want you.
我要你
What?
什么？
- SirJohn is here. - Show him in, please.
- 约翰爵士来了 - 请他进来
- I want you to make love with me. - Pardon?
- 我想和你上床 - 什么？
Nothing.
没什么
- Will you take me to bed, Archie? - No. Sorry.
- 阿奇，你会和我上床吗？ - 不会，抱歉
Bye, Uncle.
再见，叔叔
He's pleading not guilty...
他不会认罪
so you're safe until the trial.
审讯前你很安全
Leach doesn't think he did it.
利奇认为不是他做的
Ken says there's a safe deposit box key, but only George knows where it is.
肯说有一把保险箱钥匙 但只有乔治知道在哪里
Thank you, Wanda.
万达，谢谢你
- What have you found out? - Not a lot.
- 你有什么发现？ - 没什么
- You realize he's in court tomorrow? - I know that!
- 你知道他明天会上法庭？ - 我知道
So nothing, huh?
没有发现吗？
Nix.
没有
Zip.
零
Diddly. Bupkes.
毫无头绪
- Oh, it's too big. - No, it isn't, Portia.
- 太大了 - 不是
- It is enormous. - No, it isn't.
- 很巨大 - 不是
- Please, Mother. - No, absolutely not.
- 母亲，求求你 - 不是
I'm so miserable, and you just don't care.
我那么可怜但你却不在乎
Do shut up, Portia.
波席亚，住口
All I get all day is people complaining to me.
每天都有人向我埋怨
Oh, dear.
亲爱的
Archie, I want you to speak to her about plastic surgery.
阿奇，我想你和她谈谈整容手术
I do wish you'd listen to me. I want you to speak to Portia.
希望你会听我说 我想你和波席亚谈谈
Right. I'll have a word with her in the morning.
好，我早上会找她谈谈
Good night, Archie.
阿奇，晚安
Good night, Wanda.
万达，晚安
- Good night, who? - Sorry, darling.
- 你向谁说晚安？ - 对不起
Just some stupid case I've got tomorrow with some lousy old hag.
只是关于明天一些 笨案件的老太婆
Are you George Francis Thomason...
你是梅利路基普利公寓的...
of Kipling Mansions, Murray Avenue, London W9?
乔治法兰西汤玛森吗？
Yes, sir.
是
The charge is one of armed robbery. Sit down, Mr. Thomason.
你被控持械行劫 汤玛森先生，坐下
Are we ready for a committal today, Mr. Percival?
普西维先生 你准备好今天的监听会吗？
Yes, it will be under Section 62, Madam.
准备好，会用法例第62条例
That is correct-- 62.
对...62
Here are the statements, all to be fully bound, please.
这是所有证供
Stand up, Mr. Thomason.
汤玛森先生，站起来
You are hereby committed to stand trial at the Central Criminal Court.
你会在中央刑事法庭受审
There is some urgency about this case, Madam...
本案件有点紧急
as the main witness, Mrs. Eileen Coady, is elderly...
本案主要证人伊莲科迪女士 年纪老迈...
and has had serious heart difficulties recently.
她最近的心脏有问题
Is there any possibility that this case...
本案件有可能...
might be put down for an early trial?
提早审讯吗？
That would be for the listing officer at the Old Bailey.
那是排期官的责任
Take him down to the cells, please.
请带他去监狱
Yes, sir.
是
Come along, now.
来吧
Hi, hon. How are you doing? Ooh, you look great.
你在做什么？你很漂亮
I love your hair. Do you have time for a coffee?
我喜欢你的发型 你有时间喝咖啡吗？
- No, I've got to go. - Have you thought about it though?
- 不，我要走了 - 你有想过吗？
One thing: Why did he give you this? ''Eileen Coady, 69 Basil Street''?
他为什么给你这个？ “比西街69号伊莲科迪”
What does he want you to do, send her flowers?
他想你怎样做？送花给她？
Do her shopping? Show her a good time?
帮她去购物？令她快乐？
Rub her out?
谋杀她？
He wants you to rub her out?
他想你谋杀她？
He's going to kill her!
他会杀她
Fuck off, or I'll kill you.
走开，否则我会杀掉你
Limey fruits!
讨厌的英国人！
So the old lady's going to meet with an accident, Ken?
肯，老妇人会遇上意外？
- What's so funny? - Nothing.
- 是什么那么有趣？ - 没什么
It's just that wasting old ladies isn't nice.
我觉得杀死老妇人不是很好
Well, it's better than buggering people.
总比鸡奸好
I'll bet you a pound you don't kill her.
我和你打赌一镑你不会杀她
- All right. - All right.
- 好 - 好
I love watching your ass when you walk.
我喜欢看你走路时的屁股
Is that beautiful, or what?
很漂亮，不是吗？
Don't go near him! He's mine!
不要走近他！他属于我的！
A pound says you won't kill her.
我打赌一镑你不会杀她
- When could you look at it? - Well, Thursday's hopeless.
- 你什么时候能处理？ - 周四不行
My wife's going to the opera Friday evening.
周五我太太会去看歌剧
I could have a look at it then, call you at the office Saturday morning.
到时我可以来看看 周六早上我打电话给你
I'd really appreciate that. Thanks, Archie.
谢谢你
I know we're not allowed to talk. Give me a call.
我知道我们不该谈话 打电话给我吧
I can't.
我不能够
Please?
求求你
- We're not allowed to speak. - We don't have to.
- 我们不能谈话 - 我们不需要讲话
I don't want you for your conversation.
我不想听你说话
I'd love to, but--
我很想，但...
- What happened? - Got a date Friday.
- 发生什么事？ - 我周五有约会
Look here, do you mind not making that terrible noise?
你可以不发出那种声音吗？
My dogs will be having their nap.
我的狗儿们要睡午觉
Nice doggy.
很棒的狗儿
Otto, what are you doing?
奥图 ，你在做什么？
It's a Buddhist meditation technique. It focuses your aggression.
这是佛教冥想技术 能够集中你的攻击力
The monks used to do it before they went into battle.
和尚在打仗前会这样做
What kind of Buddhism is this, Otto?
奥图 ，那是什么佛教？
Asshole!
混蛋！
It's an early Tantric medita-- What is this?
- 这是早期密宗冥想... - 这是什么？
In order to get information, I might have to get friendly with him.
为了取得资料 我或许和他做朋友
Well, we're ready now, at last.
我们终于准备好了
- Good. Enjoy the opera, darling. - Your supper's in the fridge.
- 欣赏歌剧吧 - 你的晚饭在冰箱里
- Marvelous. Thank you so much. - Be good.
- 很好，谢谢 - 做个好孩子
When you say ''friendly,'' what are we talking about here?
你说好朋友是什么意思？
Cordial? Courteous? Supportive? What?
诚挚？礼貌？支持？什么？
I don't know. Let's just see what happens.
我不知道，看看到时怎样
So, friendly might include...
朋友或许包括...
actual, what, penetration, would you say?
真正的上床，不是吗？
- I don't need your jealousy now. -Jealousy?
- 你不要妒忌 - 妒忌？
- Yes. - Hey, I'm merely curious.
- 对 - 我只是好奇
Me, jealous of that fop?
我妒忌那个花花公子？
- What about my tits? - Does he get to handle them?
- 我的奶子又怎样？ - 他可以触摸它们吗？
Yes, that's my forecast. I'll stand by that.
我预计会那样
- Nuzzling? - I think $20 million is worth nuzzling.
- 用鼻子擦？ - 我认为为了二千万元是值得的
- Eighty percent chance there. - Sucking?
- 机会是百分之八十 - 吸吮呢？
- I thought you weren't jealous. - I'm not. I don't believe in jealousy.
- 我以为你不是妒忌 - 我不是，我不相信妒忌心
It's for the weak.
那是弱者的行为
One thing, though: touch his dick, and he's dead.
只要你碰他的那话儿 他就死定了
I told your father to get the car serviced.
我叫你爸爸拿汽车去维修
- Aren't we going, then? - Do shut up, Portia.
- 我们会去吗？ - 住口 ，波席亚
Hurry up.
快点
Do you despise me?
你蔑视我吗？
No, that's not a word that leaps to mind.
我不会那样说
Can I stay, then?
我可以留下来吗？
Of course. Look.
当然可以，看
- Wanda-- - I know.
- 万达... - 我知道
Your wife's coming back.
你太太回来了
No, it's not her. She'll be gone for hours.
不是她，她不会这么快回来
It's about what I said to you.
是关于我向你说过的说话
It is all right for us to speak.
我们是可以交谈的
- It is? - Provided we don't discuss the case.
- 是吗？ - 只要我们不讨论案件
Oh, fine.
好的
It's just that if anyone saw us talking--
但如果有人看见我们交谈...
But they won't.
他们不会
Sorry if I seem pompous.
抱歉我那么傲慢
Oh, you're the best, Archie.
阿奇，你是最棒的
Not yet. I'm thirsty.
等一下，我很口渴
What shall I get you?
你要喝什么？
Whiskey.
威士忌
You are the sexiest, most beautiful girl...
你是我这一生...
I have ever seen...
所见过最性感...
in my entire life.
最美丽的女子
Get me my drink.
把酒给我
So...
那么...
if George decides to change his plea...
如果乔治决定改变他的计划...
he'd tell you where the loot is first, wouldn't he?
他会告诉你赃货在哪里吧？
Darling, we mustn't talk about the trial, okay?
我们不能讨论审讯，知道吗？
I know. I just meant theoretically.
我知道 我只是在说理论上是那样
Kiss me there.
吻我那里
Oh, theoretically.
理论上
Well, if the defendant wants to change his plea...
如果被告想改为认罪...
in his instructions to his legal representative...
根据他向代表律师的指示...
the normal procedure--
正常程序...
- What's the matter? - It's wonderful, Archie.
- 什么事？ - 阿奇，很棒
- What's the matter? - You're getting me so hot.
- 什么事？ - 你令我欲火焚身
- Sorry. - I need something to drink.
- 对不起 - 我要喝些饮料
Something cold, maybe in the fridge?
一些冰的饮料，冰箱有吗？
- Champagne? - My favorite.
- 香槟？ - 我最喜欢的
Don't go away.
别走开
- What are you doing here? - Relax.
- 你在这里做什么？ - 轻松点
- Get the fuck out of here. - I heard moaning. I was worried.
- 滚开 - 我听到呻吟声，我很担心
I was faking it, you stupid jerk.
我在假装，笨蛋
Don't ever call me stupid, and I'm not jealous.
不要再叫我笨蛋，我没有妒忌
- Then leave. - Okay.
- 那就离开 - 好
It's a nice place.
这里很棒
Don't touch his dick.
不要碰他的那话儿
His wife.
他的太太
Now, for goodness' sake, get off to bed.
天啊，去睡觉吧
Oh, God, there isn't any ice.
没有冰块了
Champagne.
香槟
What's the matter?
什么事？
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Champagne, dear, to welcome you home.
香槟，欢迎你回家
Let me pour you a glass.
让我倒一杯给你
Whose is the car?
那是谁的汽车？
- The car? - Blocking the drive.
- 汽车？ - 在车道上那一辆
There you are, dear. Cheers. Nice to see you.
你回来了 ，看到你真高兴
How was the opera? Finished early?
歌剧怎样？提早结束吗？
Whose car is it?
那是谁的汽车？
Mine. It's a beauty, isn't it?
是我的，很漂亮吧？
Where did I leave my drink, Archie?
阿奇，我把酒放在哪里？
Who is this?
这是谁？
- Don't you know? - How do you do, Mrs. Leach?
- 你不知道吗？ - 利奇太太，你好吗？
I'm Harvey Manfredin St.John.
我是哈里曼佛圣约翰
- I'm with the C.I.A. - C.I.A.?
- 我隶属中央情报局 - 中央情报局？
That's correct, ma'am.
对，太太
I was just telling your husband here...
我在想上你们美丽的厕所前
before I had to go to your beautiful bathroom...
告诉你的丈夫...
we've got a high-ranking K.G.B. defector...
我们在附近的房子里
in a safe house near here.
有一位苏联国家安全委员会 变节者
We're debriefing him as of now...
我们正在向他盘问
and we're just checking...
我们在检查...
all the houses in the neighborhood.
附近所有房屋
- For what? - For K.G.B.
- 为什么？ - 苏联国家安全委员会
- Is there any danger? - No, no.
- 有危险吗？ - 没有
Not now.
现在没有
We--
我们...
We just want to keep everyone informed.
我们只是想通知大家
So, Archie, thanks for the drink.
阿奇，谢谢你的酒
Sorry to have troubled you, folks. I'll see myself out.
抱歉打扰你们，我要离开了
- Keep everyone informed? - So there's no panic, ma'am.
- 通知大家？ - 太太，不用担心
- But isn't it a secret? - You have no idea how secret.
- 但这不是秘密吗？ - 你不知道有多秘密
Why are you telling everyone?
你为什么告诉大家？
It's a smoke screen?
这是烟幕？
- What? - Double bluff.
- 什么？ - 虚张声势
You obviously don't know anything about intelligence work, lady.
你不知道情报工作是怎样
It's an XK Red 2 7 technique.
这是XK红色27号技术
My father was in the Secret Service, Mr. Manfredin St.John.
我父亲是情报人员
I know perfectly well that you don't keep the general public informed...
我很清楚当你在盘问一个 苏联国家安全委员会成员时...
when you are debriefing K.G.B. defectors in a safe house.
你们是不会通知公众的
You don't, huh?
是吗？
Not unless you're congenitally insane or irretrievably stupid.
除非你是疯了或很笨
- Don't call me stupid. - Why on earth not?
- 不要说我笨 - 为什么？
You English are so superior, aren't you?
你们英国人觉得自己很优越吧？
Would you like to know where you'd be without us...
你想知道如没有美国保护你们...
the old U.S. of A., to protect you?
你们会变成怎样吗？
The smallest fucking province in the Russian empire, that's what!
你们只会成为俄罗斯帝国的 一个小县罢了 ！
So don't call me stupid, lady. Just thank me.
女士，不要说我笨 你只用感谢我
Well, thank you for popping in and protecting us.
谢谢你进来保护我们
If it wasn't for us, you'd all be speaking German, singing--
如果不是我们 你们现在会说德语
That's my brother covering for me.
那是我的哥哥帮我掩护
Get rid of your wife and get my necklace.
摆脱你的太太，去拿我的项链
Necklace, right. I'll think of something to get rid of her.
对，我会想办法摆脱她
- Who are you talking to? - Myself, darling.
- 你在和谁说话？ - 我自己
- Who was that shouting? - The brother of a friend of mine.
- 那是什么叫声？ - 我朋友的哥哥
- Archie, who on earth? - I don't know.
- 阿奇，究竟是谁？ - 我不知道
Extraordinary. He rang the bell, I opened the door.
真有趣，他按门铃，我打开门
- I need a drink. - Let's go to the pub.
- 我需要饮料 - 我们去酒吧
- What? - Let's go to the pub.
- 什么？ - 我们去酒吧
- Would you like to come, Portia? - We haven't been there in 1 5 years.
- 波席亚，你想来吗？ - 我们15年来没有去过了
It would be nice for Portia to see it now.
现在应该让波席亚见识一下
Honestly, Archie.
阿奇，你不是认真的吧？
- What on earth is the matter? - I thought the picture was falling.
- 究竟发生什么事？ - 我以为画快要掉下来
- Pull yourself together. - It's all right. It's secure now.
- 镇静点 - 现在安全了
What's this?
这是什么？
Thanks, Portia. Well done. Coming with us?
谢谢，你会来吗？
- What was that? - A kind of necklace.
- 那是什么？ - 项链
- What's going on? - Nothing, dear. Let's go.
- 发生什么事？ - 没什么，来吧
- Can I see that? - What?
- 我可以看看吗？ - 什么？
In your hand.
你的手
Your other hand.
你的另一只手
- Portia, go to your room. - Are we going to the pub?
- 波席亚，去你的房间 - 我们会去酒吧吗？
I can explain. I left some papers at the office.
我可以解释 我在办公室遗留了一些文件
Now! And they sent a new girl up.
他们派了一个新女职员来
- Oh, Archie. - Really, she's Canadian.
- 阿奇 - 真的，她是加拿大人
- She mentioned it was her birthday. - It's lovely. Thank you.
- 她说今天是她的生日 - 很漂亮，谢谢你
It's even got a ''W'' for Wendy.
甚至刻有W字母
Oh, I'm so glad you like it, darling.
我很高兴你喜欢
It's the most beautiful thing you've ever given me.
这是你送给我最漂亮的礼物
This isn't like you.
这不像你
- Are you fucking crazy? - Hey, I saved your ass.
- 你疯了吗？ - 我救了你一命
I had him right where I wanted him, you asshole!
我差点哄到他，混蛋！
I give you one fucking thing to do, Otto.
奥图 ，我有工作给你做
You're supposed to drive me here. Shut up!
你应该载我来这里，闭嘴
Oh, relax.
放松
Hold on. It's for you.
等一下，找你的
Not at the moment, no.
现在不行
Yes, I'm not quite sure when I'll be able to get hold of that.
我不肯定我什么时候能够
Yes, I do appreciate that. Yes, as soon as possible.
好，谢谢你，对，尽快
Well, that would be very nice, obviously.
那样很好
So see you soon, I hope?
我们很快又会再见吧？
Bye, Frank.
再见
Easy, Maggie.
玛吉，放松
Calm down.
冷静下来
Come here.
过来
Smell, Maggie, smell.
玛吉，嗅嗅吧
Now.
现在
Kill!
杀！
We therefore commit its body to the ground...
我们现在把它入土为安
earth to earth, ashes to ashes...
尘归尘
dust to dust...
土归土
in sure and certain hope of the resurrection...
希望它会复生
to eternal life.
找到永生
Hello, honey. What happened?
亲爱的，发生什么事？
- Nothing. - What's that?
- 没什么 - 那是什么？
- Not Granny? - Not yet.
- 不是祖母吧 - 还没有
Who's it for, then?
那是给谁的？
A fish. A Frenchman. A phone operator.
一条鱼、一个法国人 电话接线生
- Friend. - A four-legged one?
- 是朋友 - 四脚朋友？
- Where's my sister? - She's in the--
- 我妹妹在哪里？ - 她在...
- Thank you. - Lavatory.
- 谢谢 - 洗手间
- Anything? - What? No.
- 有什么事？ - 什么？没什么
- Why are you here? - I'm here because I'm bored.
- 你为什么在这里？ - 我在这里因为我很无聊
Bored wandering around this God-awful city...
在这个讨厌的城市闲逛闷死了
shoving George's ugly pic--
移开乔治的丑陋照片...
talking to a lot of snotty, stuck-up, intellectually inferior British faggots.
和一些低层次的英国人谈话
Jesus, they're uptight.
他们很不安
They get rigor mortis in the prime of life in this country.
他们在壮年时肌肉就僵硬
Standing there with their hair clenched.
他们就那样呆站着
Counting the seconds till the week ends...
等着一周的结束
so they can all dress up like ballerinas and...
那么他们能打扮漂亮
whip themselves into a frenzy at the flat at 4.
然后去玩乐
''2B, St.--''
“2B...”
To be honest...
老实说...
I hate them.
我讨厌他们
I mean, pretending they're so fucking lawyer--
佯装他们是律师...
so fucking superior...
自以为很优越...
with those phony accents.
操着一口假口音
Not you, Ken. You've got a beautiful speaking voice.
肯，我不是说你 你的声音很漂亮
When it works.
当你没有口吃时
Son of a bitch!
混蛋！
So, wanna have some lunch?
你想吃午饭吗？
- Have you heard from him? - Who?
- 他有联络你吗？ - 谁？
- Archie. - No, I have to finish my hair!
- 阿奇 - 没有，我要染头发
Nothing? I'm out of here! No plans to see him?
没有？我走了 你不打算见他吗？
Okay. Bye, bro!
再见
Bye, Wanda!
万达，再见
Oh, sorry.
对不起
- What? - It wasn't theirs to sell.
- 什么？ - 那不是属于他们的
An old lady gave it to them to engrave. She's about 80 and dying.
一位老妇交给他们刻字 她快八十也快死了
It's of great sentimental value. Somebody put it in the display cabinet.
这个很有纪念价值 有人把它放在展示柜里
- That's their problem. - Not really.
- 那是他们的问题 - 不可以那样说
- You paid for it. - They do accept their mistake.
- 你付钱买下的 - 他们接受他们的错误
They're offering you this to replace it. It's three times as valuable.
他们想用这个代替它 这个的价值高三倍
This is the nicest thing you've ever given me, which I absolutely love.
这是你给我的礼物之中最棒的
Now you want me to give it back and replace it with something vulgar.
现在你想我交还它 和用这样俗不可耐的东西代替
- I don't want you to give it back. - Well, they can't have it.
- 我不想你交还它 - 他们不能拿回去
Tell them they can't have it.
告诉他们不能
You're the bloody barrister!
你是律师
Oh, Archie, it's beautiful.
阿奇，很漂亮
It's just beautiful.
很漂亮
Oh, my God! Look!
我的天！你看！
Oh, Archie, it's beautiful.
阿奇，很漂亮
Isn't it wonderful?
很棒吧？
- Whose is it? - Belongs to someone at the chambers.
- 是谁的？ - 属于办公室的一位同事
And where are they?
他们在哪里？
Hong Kong. Gone for weeks.
去了香港几个星期
Nice rug, Archie.
阿奇，很不错的地毯
May I?
可以吗？
- What are you doing? - The polka, I think.
- 你在做什么？ - 我在跳波尔卡舞
You make me feel free.
你令我感到很自由
Free?
自由？
Do you have any idea what it's like being English?
你知道身为英国人是怎样吗？
Being so correct all the time? Being so stifled...
时常都很正确和被压制？
by this dread of doing the wrong thing?
时常都害怕做错事？
Of saying to someone, ''Are you married?''
问人“你是否已婚？”
and hearing, ''My wife left me this morning''?
怎料对方说 “太太今早离开了我？”
Or saying, ''Do you have children?'' And being told...
或问人“你有没有孩子？”
''They all burned to death on Wednesday.''
对方却说“他们在星期三 都被烧死了”
You see, Wanda, we're all...
万达，你可以看到...
terrified of embarrassment.
我们都害怕尴尬
That's why we're so...
所以我们...
dead.
都那么死寂
Most of my friends are dead. We have these piles of corpses to dinner.
我大部分朋友都很沉闷 就像和死尸共膳一样
But you're alive, God bless you, and I want to be.
但你充满生气，我也想那样
I'm so fed up with all this.
我厌倦所有事情
I want to make love with you.
我想和你上床
I'm a good lover. At least...
我是个好情人
I used to be, back in the early 1 4th century.
至少我在十四世纪时是
Can we go to bed?
我们可以上床吗？
Yeah.
好
Hang on. Mind your head.
等一下，小心你的头
Oh, I think I love you.
我认为我爱你
- Can I ask you a question? - Anything.
- 我可以问你一个问题吗？ - 什么也可以
Where's my locket?
我的项链在哪里？
- I couldn't get it. - What?
- 我拿不到 - 什么？
Wendy wouldn't give it back. Look, I got you this instead.
温迪不肯交还它 我买了这个给你
- Like it? - No, Archie.
- 你喜欢吗？ - 不喜欢
I have to have mine.
我要拿回我的项链
Why?
为什么？
My mother gave it to me...
我母亲临死前...
on her deathbed.
给我的
I'm sorry. All right, darling.
对不起
- I'll get it for you. - You promise?
- 我会拿回给你 - 你保证吗？
I'll think of something.
我会想办法
Sex is very difficult for me...
跟我不完全信任的人上床
with somebody that I don't trust completely.
对我来说是很困难
I promise I'll get it, okay?
我保证我会取回它
I love you, Archie!
阿奇，我爱你
I've loved you ever since the first second I saw you.
我对你一见钟情
- What was that? - What?
- 那是什么？ - 什么？
Your brother didn't bring you here this time, did he?
你哥哥这次没有带你来吧？
- No. - He has no idea?
- 没有 - 他不知道？
He doesn't have a clue.
- 他完全不知道
What?
- 什么？
- He is so dumb. - Really?
- 他很笨 - 真的？
He thought the Gettysburg Address was where Lincoln lived.
他以为林肯住在盖底斯堡
All those terrible lies he told about the CIA.
他讲关于中央情报局的谎话 真是差劲
So painful.
很痛苦
And when he heard your daughter's name was Portia...
当他听到你女儿叫波席亚...
he said, ''Why did they name her after a car?''
他问为什么用汽车名字命名
I love the way you laugh.
我喜欢你笑的样子
I love you. You're funny.
我爱你，你很有趣
How come a girl as bright as you could have a brother who's so--
怎么这样聪明的女孩的哥哥 会这么...
Don't call me stupid.
不要说我笨
Jesus Christ!
我的天！
- Come on! - Ouch!
- 来吧！ - 很痛
Come on!
来吧！
I'll deal with you later.
我稍后应付你
What have you done with her?
你对她做了什么？
She's all right.
她没事
Now, apologize.
道歉吧
- What? - Apologize.
- 什么？ - 道歉
- Oh, shit! - Are you totally deranged?
- 糟了 - 你精神错乱吗？
You pompous, stuck-up...
你这个自大狂妄
snot-nosed, English...
不可一世...
giant, twerp...
笨蛋...
scumbag, fuck face, dick-head, asshole!
不知廉耻的混蛋
How very interesting.
真有趣
You're a true vulgarian, aren't you?
你真的很俗不可耐，不是吗？
You're the vulgarian, you fuck! Now, apologize!
是你俗不可耐，道歉吧
Me to you?
我向你道歉？
Apologize.
道歉
All right, I apologize.
好，我道歉
- You're really sorry? - I'm really, really sorry.
- 你真的感到内疚吗？ - 我真的感到抱歉
I apologize unreservedly.
我诚心地道歉
- You take it back? - I do. I offer...
- 你真的收回刚才的说话？ - 对
a complete and utter retraction.
我完全收回我的说话
The imputation was totally without basis in fact...
刚才的毁谤毫无根据...
and was in no way fair comment and was motivated...
那不是正确的评判 而且动机是...
purely by malice, and I deeply regret...
敌意，如果我的言语...
any distress that my comments may have caused you or your family.
为你和你家人 带来不安，深感歉意
And I hereby undertake not to repeat...
我承诺将来不会...
any such slander at any time in the future.
再重覆任何这样的行为
Okay.
好
You said you loved him!
你说你爱他
That's right! Now, here's a multiple choice question for you.
对，你要回答这个选择问题
A: Wanda was lying.
甲 ，万达在说谎
B: Wanda was telling the truth!
乙，万达说的是真相
Which one are you gonna pick?
你会选哪一个？
What was the first one? You told me you were not planning to see him.
第一个是什么？ 你说不打算见他
Because I knew you'd come along and fuck it up!
因为我知道你会坏事
I was dealing with something delicate.
我在处理很敏感的事情
I'm setting up a guy who's incredibly important to us--
我在向一个重要的人下手
who's going to tell me where the loot is...
他会告诉我赃货在哪里...
and if they're gonna come and arrest you-- and you come loping in...
他们或许会来拘捕你 你却像...
like Rambo without a jockstrap and dangle him out a fifth-floor window.
没穿护身衣的蓝波般闯进来 把他吊在五层楼的窗外
Now, was that smart?
那样很聪明吗？
- Okay. - Was it shrewd?
- 好 - 很糟吗？
Was it good tactics or was it stupid?
那是很棒还是很笨的策略？
Don't call me stupid.
不要说我笨
Oh, right! To call you stupid would be an insult to stupid people!
说你笨就是侮辱愚蠢的人
I've known sheep that could outwit you.
我见过比你聪明的羊
I've worn dresses with higher IQs.
我穿过智商比你高的裙子
But you think you're an intellectual, don't you, ape?
但你自以为是学者吧？猿猴
Apes don't read philosophy.
猿猴不会看哲学书的
Yes, they do. They just don't understand it.
它们会看，只是不明白
Now, let me correct you on a couple things, okay?
让我向你解释几样事情，好吗？
Aristotle was not Belgian.
阿里士多德不是比利时人
The central message of Buddhism is not ''Every man for himself.''
佛教的主旨不是自私
And the London Underground is not a political movement.
伦敦地下铁不是政治运动
Those are all mistakes. I looked 'em up.
那些全是错的 我查过的
Now, you have just assaulted...
你刚袭击了...
the one man who can keep you out of jail and make you rich.
能够令你不用坐牢而且致富的人
So what are you gonna do about it?
你会怎样做？
What would an intellectual do?
学者会怎样做？
What would Plato do?
柏拉图会怎样做？
- Apologize. - Pardon me?
- 道歉 - 什么？
What?
什么？
- Apologize! - Right!
- 道歉！ - 对！
I'm sorry.
对不起
No. Not to me, to Archie.
不是向我道歉，向阿奇道歉
And make it good or we're dead.
诚心地道歉，否则我们死定了
I'm so very, very--
我非常...
Fuck you!
你去见鬼吧！
Very, very--
非常...
Hello, Mr. Burglar. Going somewhere?
小偷先生，你好，你去哪里？
Thought you could rob Mr. Leach, eh? Well, I'm gonna teach you a lesson.
你以为你可以抢劫利奇先生？ 我会教训你
He just happens to be a very good friend of mine...
他是我很好的朋友
and he's going to be very pleased with me when he finds you...
当他发现你将被我抓去警局时...
all tied up and ready for the police.
他会很高兴
And don't call me Otto. To you, I am Mr.--
不要叫我奥图 ，我是...
Oh, my God!
我的天！
I'm sorry.
对不起
Please. I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I didn't know it was you.
我不知道是你
How could I know it was you?
我怎会知道是你？
I mean, how could you expect me to guess?
我怎会猜到是你？
You stupid jerk. What the fuck are you doing...
笨蛋，你在做什么？
robbing your own house?
抢劫自己的房子？
You asshole!
混蛋！
You stupid, stiff, pompous, English--
你这个闷蛋自大的英国人
I'm sorry.
对不起
God almighty!
我的天！
Bloody hell!
怎会这样！
Darling!
亲爱的！
Are you hurt?
你有没有受伤？
Speak to me. Are you hurt?
跟我说话，你有没有受伤？
Can't you speak?
你不能说话吗？
What has happened?
发生什么事？
Archie, we've been burgled.
阿奇，我们被抢劫
- Oh, no! - Well, are you hurt?
- 不！ - 你有没有受伤？
No, I'm fine. Bit of a headache.
我没事，只是有少许头痛
I came in here. Somebody hit me, tied me up with a--
我进来后有人打我的头 并把我绑起来
My God, is that the time?
我的天，这么晚了？
What?
什么事？
- I didn't realize it was quite so late. - What?
- 我不知道原来这么晚了 - 什么？
- I'm late for a conference. - A conference?
- 我要出席会议 - 会议？
- You've just been attacked! - It's nothing. I must fly. Sorry.
- 你刚被人袭击 - 我没事，我要去走了
I'll help you tidy up when I get back. Hello, Portia.
我回来后我帮你收拾房子 波席亚，你好
What's happened?
发生什么事？
Your father has finally gone completely mental.
你父亲终于疯了
Thank you so much.
谢谢你
- Champagne? - Okay.
- 要香槟吗？ - 好
To us.
为我们干杯
Well, I went back to the house and guess who--
我回家后，你猜是谁...
Let's make love.
我们做爱吧
Well, if you absolutely insist.
如果你坚持要的话，好吧
- No. - What?
- 不 - 什么？
Here on the rug.
在地毯上
I'll be right back. Get undressed.
我很快回来，你先脱下衣服
Why not?
有何不可？
Why not indeed.
对
- Afterwards-- - Yeah?
- 然后... - 怎样？
Let's go to South America.
我们一起去南美洲
- What? - Let's fly to South America.
- 什么？ - 我们一起去南美洲
Why South America?
为什么要去南美洲？
Okay, Iceland.
那么冰岛吧
What do you really want out of life?
你究竟想要什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
Why do I like you so much?
我为什么那么喜欢你？
Do you speak Italian?
你会说意大利话吗？
I am Italian!
我是意大利人
But it's such an ugly language.
但那是很难听的语言
How about Russian?
俄罗斯话怎样？
- Are you rich? - No, I'm afraid not.
- 你有钱吗？ - 我没钱的
- What about the house? - That's Wendy's. She's the rich one.
- 房子呢？ - 是属于温迪的，她很有钱
- What the hell are you doing? - I might ask you the same question.
- 你在做什么？ - 我或许会问你相同的问题
Who are you?
你是谁？
- What? - Get your clothes on.
- 什么？ - 穿回衣服
- Will you leave immediately, please? - What?
- 请你立即离开好吗？ - 什么？
You're in the wrong flat.
你来错地方
This flat belongs to Patrick Balfour.
这个公寓属于派崔克巴佛
He's in Hong Kong. He lent me the key. Now, get out!
他去了香港，他借钥匙给我 请你离开！
But we leased it from the agents last weekend.
但我们上周从管理员那租下这里
Yes, well, obviously that changes things a bit.
那很明显的，那改变了一切
Aren't you Archie Leach?
你不是阿奇利奇吗？
What?
什么？
You bought our house in Lissendon Gardens.
你买下我们在利斯顿的房子
Hazel and Ian Johnson.
希娑和伊恩强森
What a coincidence!
真巧合
How nice to see you.
幸会
- Hello? - Wanda, it's Archie. Listen.
- 找谁？ - 万达，是阿奇
I can't see you anymore. I've got to end it. I'm sorry.
我不能再见你，我们完了 对不起
What?
什么？
I'm sorry.
对不起
- Okay. - Oh, no. Please.
- 好吗？ - 不要
- Look, I want to apologize. - I just finished it, all right?
- 我想道歉 - 我们已经分手，好吗？
Okay, just-- Wait. Where are you going?
等一下，你去哪里？
I just ended it, for Christ's sake! Will you leave me alone?
我们已分手，你不要再烦我
- I've just ended it, all right? - Wait!
- 我们已分手，好吗？ - 等一下
- I just want to say I'm sorry. - It's all over!
- 我只是想道歉 - 我们完了
-Jesus Christ! Someone help me! - Will you calm down?
- 我的天，救我 - 你冷静下来好吗？
Please, believe me. Don't beat me up again.
求你相信我，不要再打我
I've had a terrible day.
我今天很不高兴
- Will you shut up? -Jesus Christ! Don't kill me, please.
- 你住口好吗？ - 天！不要杀我
Shut up then. Okay.
住口
Look, I just wanna apologize...
我只是想为了...
sincerely for when I dangled you out the window.
我把你吊出窗户的事向你道歉
I'm really, really-- Well, it was not a nice thing to do.
我真的很...我不应该那样做
And then when I attacked you in there, well, I'm really--
然后我在那里袭击你 我真的很...
How could I know you were trying to rob your own house?
我怎知道你想抢劫自己的房子？
- I was just trying to help. - Yes. Thanks.
- 你只是想帮忙 - 是，谢谢
- I wanted you to trust me. - Please, it was my fault.
- 我想你相信我 - 那是我的错
- That's true. - Yeah.
- 你说得对 - 对
Now, about my sister.
关于我的妹妹
She's a very sexy girl.
她很性感
I understand you wanting to play around with her.
我明白你想和她发展
It's okay. I was wrong.
那没关系，我是错的
I'm sorry I was jealous. Just go ahead.
抱歉我妒忌，你去追求她吧
Pork away, pal. Fuck her blue.
和她上床吧
I like you, Archie. I just wanna help.
阿奇，我喜欢你，我只是想帮忙
Oh, God!
天！
I did it.
我成功了
I did it! Lovely!
我成功了 ！
Unbe-fucking-lieveable!
难以置信
Thomason!
汤玛森！
You've done well, my son.
你做的很好
Now, here's the plan.
计划是这样的
You get four tickets this evening for Rio, first class.
你去买四张今晚去里约热内卢的 头等机票
Then--
然后...
Yeah, four. We get rid of Otto later.
对，四张，稍后才摆脱奥图
Then, back to the flat. Pack, collect me.
然后回来公寓收拾行李
Then to the Cathcart Towers Hotel to pick up the jewels.
然后去卡思卡取珠宝
Unbe-fucking-lievable!
难以置信
Oh, it's so exciting. I can't believe it.
很刺激，我不能相信
He's safe.
他很安全
Oh, I'm going to be late for court.
我快迟到了
Hello? Oh, hello, Otto.
有人吗？奥图 ，你好
No, she just left.
她刚离开了
And, Otto, you owe me a--
奥图 ，你欠我...
What?
什么？
You owe me a pound.
你欠我一镑
Not Granny?
不是祖母吧？
Met with an accident.
遇上意外了
- Bullshit! You're lying! - Come on.
- 胡说！你在说谎！ - 说吧
Dead?
死了？
Heart attack.
心脏病发
I don't believe this.
我不相信
George'll be out this afternoon.
乔治今天下午就能离开
We'll all go out to Heathrow, collect the loot, and then--
我们会去希思罗机场取赃货 然后...
All thanks...
全部都是...
to me.
我的功劳
So, the loot's at the airport, is it, Ken?
肯，赃货在机场吗？
What's happening?
发生什么事？
Well, Ken...
肯...
I'm going to ask you some questions while I eat my chips.
我在吃薯条时要问你一些问题
First, who is the philosopher...
第一题，哪个哲学家...
who developed the concept of the ''superman''...
在他的书中
in Also sprach Zarathustra?
发展出 “超人” 的概念？
No?
不知道？
That's a chip up the nose, I'm afraid.
我要把马铃薯条塞进鼻子
Friedrich Nietzsche. Next.
是尼采，下一个问题
In which book did Nietzsche claim...
尼采在哪一本书中...
that almost all higher culture is based on cruelty?
提出所有高级文化 都是以残酷为依据？
Are you thinking, or are you in mid-stutter?
你在思想还是又口吃？
You're mad.
你是疯的
Beyond Good and Evil.
Beyond Good and Evil
I guess I'll have to ask you an easy one, huh?
我要问你一个简单的问题
Okay, um--
好...
Let me think.
让我想想
Where are the diamonds? I'll give you a clue.
钻石在哪里？我给你一个线索
Somewhere around the airport.
在机场某个地方
- I'm n-- - No hassle. There's plenty of time.
- 我不... - 不用急，还有很多时间
I'll just sit here and eat my chips until you tell me.
我会边吃着薯条一直到你告诉我
The English contribution to world cuisine: the chip.
英国对美食的贡献就是薯条
What do the English usually eat with chips...
英国人会用什么跟 薯条一齐吃...
to make them more interesting?
而令它们好吃一点？
Wait a moment!
等一下
It's fish, isn't it?
是鱼吧？
Here, boy. Down the hatch.
又一条
Delicious.
很美味
You b--
你...
Better eat the green one? Okay.
最好吃绿色的？
What's this one's name?
这个叫什么名字？
Well, not Wanda, anyway.
不是万达
I'm going to call her Lunch.
我会叫她做午饭
Hello, Lunch.
午饭，你好
Avoid the green ones.
避开绿色那一些
They're not ripe yet.
它们还没熟透
Now, you were in court, were you not, Inspector...
法医官在庭上发表证据时...
when the forensic evidence was read?
你在法庭上吗？
- Yes, sir. - And the fact that...
- 是 - 事实上...
Mr. Thomason was installing windows the previous weekend...
汤玛森先生在之前的一个周末 安装窗户...
would account, would it not...
引致玻璃碎片...
for the presence of small particles of glass on his trousers?
掉在他的裤子上吗？
No hurry, Inspector. Please do take your time.
警官，你不用急着回答
I'm almost full.
我很饱
- Almost. - Stop!
- 差不多 - 停止
Please, don't.
不要
Come on, Wanda. Gullet time.
万达，进食时间
What are the names of those hotels that are right by the airport?
机场附近的饭店名字是什么？
What are they? The Airway Sheraton, The Post House, The Cathcart Towers--
喜来登饭店？卡思卡饭店？...
The Cathcart Towers? Yes?
卡思卡饭店？
- Yes. - In a safe deposit box?
- 对 - 在保险箱里？
Yes.
是
- What? - Where's the key?
- 什么？ - 钥匙在哪里？
It's in the tank.
在鱼缸里
Where?
哪里？
- In the t-- - Treasure chest!
- 在... - 珠宝箱里！
You m-m--
你...
murdering--
谋杀
I'll kill you!
我会杀死你
Sorry, Ken, but your answer was incorrect.
抱歉，肯，你的答案是错的
Still, you really did think it was in there, didn't you?
你真的认为它在里面吗？
What?
什么？
Hello?
找谁？
- I know where the diamonds are. - Where?
- 我知道钻石在哪里 - 在哪里？
Where's the key?
钥匙在哪里？
I've got it.
我有钥匙
How soon can you get to George's apartment?
你最快什么时候 能到达乔治的寓所？
You are Wanda Gershwitz of Kipling Mansions...
你是住在伦敦梅利路...
Murray Road, London, West Nine?
基普利公寓的万达格肖维吗？
- Yes. - Will you tell the court, please...
- 是 - 请你告诉法庭...
how do you know the defendant?
你怎样认识被告？
We've had a relationship for two years.
我们有两年亲密关系
Relationship?
亲密关系？
We're lovers, your lord.
我们是恋人
Miss Gershwitz, on the fourth of March of this year...
小姐，在今年三月四日早上
in the morning, where were you?
你在哪里？
I was at the apartment at Murray Road.
我在梅利路的公寓里
And were you by yourself or was there anyone else present?
你独自一人 还是有别的人在场？
No, somebody else was there.
还有别人
- Who was that? - My brother.
- 是谁？ - 我的哥哥
And did your--
你的...
Your brother?
你的哥哥？
My brother.
我的哥哥
Yes.
是
And--
而你...
Are you quite sure it was your brother?
你很肯定那是你的哥哥？
Mr. Leach, I'm sure Miss Gershwitz can recognize her brother.
利奇先生，我肯定格肖维小姐 可以认得她的哥哥
She's had a relationship with him all her life.
她认识了他一辈子
Much obliged, my lord.
是，大人
Was there anyone else present that morning?
那个早上还有别的人在场吗？
- Yes, George was there. - Thank you.
- 有，乔治也在场 - 谢谢你
- But he left about five to 7:00. - Wanda.
- 但他在六点五十五分就离开 - 万达...
I wonder--
我想知道...
Yes, Mr. Leach?
利奇先生，什么事？
When you say five to 7:00, Miss Gershwitz...
你说六点五十五分
how can you be so sure?
你为什么那么肯定？
Oh, I looked at the clock, 'cause I was saying to myself...
因为我当时看过时钟
''Where could he be going at five to 7:00 with that sawed-off shotgun?''
我对我自己说他在六点五十五分 带着锯短的手枪去哪里？
Darling!
亲爱的！
- Mr. Leach. ''Darling''? - Yes, dear?
- 利奇， “亲爱的” ？ - 什么，甜心？
You bitch! You fucking bitch!
你这个混蛋
Restrain that man.
制止那个人
- Restrain this man. - Come here, you bastard!
- 制止这个人 - 混蛋！过来
Clear the court. I'm adjourning this matter for now.
退庭，我现在把审讯押后
- Take the prisoner below. - Clear the court!
- 带犯人离开 - 退庭！
Officers, arrest that man!
警员 ，拘捕那个人
Clear the court!
退庭
Bloody hell!
可恶
It's my husband. He's been hit.
我的丈夫被打伤
You made it. Good. Bit of a knock, I'm afraid.
你做得很好
I have never been so humiliated in my life.
我从没试过那么受辱
You can stick this marriage right in your bottom.
我们的婚姻完蛋了
I'll see you in court.
在法庭上见
Yes.
是
Well, that's it, then.
就是这样
- What? - We've got to talk.
- 什么事？ - 我们要谈谈
You tell those pigs to fuck off!
你叫这些笨蛋走开
Fuck off, pigs.
走开
Did you hear what I said? Fuck off.
你们听到我说什么吗？走开
- What's she up to, George? - What are you up to?
- 乔治，她怎样了？ - 你怎么了？
You called her darling and Wanda.
你叫她“亲爱的”和 “万达”
I've been helping her get her evidence straight.
我在帮她正确地说出证据
- It slipped out. - You've been coaching her?
- 一时冲口而出 - 你一直在教她？
What do you think? Look, we've got ten minutes.
你认为怎样？我们有十分钟
They're gonna find you guilty, right?
他们会判你有罪吧？
If you plead guilty now, tell them where the loot is...
如果你现在认罪 告诉他们赃货在哪里
you may get away with eight years, out in five-and-a-half.
你或许只用判八年牢 五年半就能出狱
What if I tell them about Otto and Wanda?
如果我供出奥图和万达又怎样？
- They both did it? - Yeah.
- 他们有份？ - 是
Great. All right. Maybe six years, out in four.
很好，或许只判六年牢 四年就能出狱
So where are the diamonds?
钻石在哪里？
- Where's Bartlett? - Upstairs trying to calm things down.
- 巴勒在哪里？ - 他在楼上
So, where are they?
它们在哪里？
Tell Bartlett Ken knows where they are.
告诉巴勒，肯知道在哪里
It'd be a lot quicker if you told me.
如果你直接告诉我会方便一点
Okay, I'll tell Bartlett. Where's Ken?
我会告诉巴勒，肯在哪里？
He's at the flat.
他在公寓里
Thank you for all your help. I'll be right out.
谢谢你的帮忙，我很快出来
Taxi! Please! Shit.
计程车！可恶
- Come on. - What?
- 来吧 - 什么？
- Let's go. - Where?
- 我们走吧 - 去哪里？
- Buenos Aires. - What?
- 布宜诺斯 - 什么？
We're going to George's flat first. Get in.
我们先去乔治的公寓，上车
- Got your passport? - Yeah.
- 你有护照吗？ - 有
Check the briefcase for mine.
在我的手提包 看看我的护照在不在
Get your head down.
趴下
So you robbed the jewelers...
你抢劫珠宝商...
turned one of your lovers over to the police...
向警方供出你其中一个情人
kept the other one on to help you find the diamonds...
叫另一个帮你找钻石
and when he does, you commit perjury in the High Court, right?
当他在找的时候 你在法庭发假誓，对吗？
Come on, Archie. Everybody does it in America.
阿奇，在美国大家都是那样
Well, not in this country, they don't!
在这个国家却不行
Oh, right. Like nobody lies in England. Like Margaret Thatcher never lied.
对，英国人没说过谎 柴侄夫人没说过谎
Look, you lied to me right from the moment we met.
我们相遇那一刻你已骗我
- You just wanted to get me into bed. - I fell in love with you.
- 你只是想和我上床 - 我爱上了你
How come you dumped me then?
那么你为什么抛弃我？
I wasn't rich enough, remember?
因为我不够有钱，记得吗？
- Say something in Russian. - No.
- 用俄罗斯话说话 - 不
What are you thinking?
你在想什么？
I'm just trying to think of one good reason why...
我在想一个好原因...
I should take you to South America with me.
我为什么要带你去南美洲
How about...
这个怎样...
because I have the key to the safety deposit box.
因为我有保险箱的钥匙
That's a good reason.
那是一个好原因
- What do we do about Otto? - I'll handle Otto.
- 奥图怎样？ - 我会处理他
- Be careful. He's dangerous. - So am I.
- 小心，他很危险的 - 我也是
Keep it running.
继续
- Why did you bring him? - Otto, just wait!
- 你为什么带他来？ - 奥图 ，等一下
I'm beginning to think you like that fruit.
我开始认为你喜欢那个傻瓜
Let's get the diamonds!
去拿钻石吧
Ken?
肯？
Are you Ken?
你是肯吗？
How do you do? I'm George's barrister.
你好吗？我是乔治的律师
What's happened?
发生什么事？
- Oh, my God! - Asshole!
- 我的天！ - 混蛋！
What the bloody hell do you think--
你在想什么...
All right, then.
好吧
Where have they gone? Quick.
他们去了哪里？快点
What?
什么？
Are you all right?
你有没有事？
- Where have they gone? - They've gone to the Cathcart--
- 他们去了哪里？ - 他们去了卡思卡...
- Are you ill? - No, no.
- 你病了吗？ - 不是...
What?
什么？
Have you got a stutter?
你有口吃吗？
Yeah.
是
- A bit. - Okay, fine. Don't worry.
- 有一点 - 没关系
Do you know where they've gone?
你知道他们去了哪里吗？
Fine. Where?
好，哪里？
The Ca-- Hotel.
卡...饭店
Hotel? Which hotel?
饭店？哪一间饭店？
Go on. It's okay.
继续，没关系
All right. Wait.
好，慢着
Slowly. Very slowly.
慢慢说
No hurry.
不用急
Sing it.
说出来吧
Plenty of time.
还有很多时间
Oh, come on! I'm sorry.
快点！对不起
Wait.
等一下
Here, write it.
写出来
Cathcart Towers Hotel?
卡思卡饭店？
Where is it?
它在哪里？
Here, again.
写出来
Heathrow Airport.
希思罗机场
Hey! What's the idea?
这是怎么回事？
- You can't stay there. - Frightfully sorry.
- 你不能留在那里 - 对不起
Take it. It's yours.
拿去，是你的
Thank you so much. British Airways to Rio?
谢谢 去里约热内卢的闸口在哪里？
Rio. Terminal four, sir.
第四个闸口
Thank you.
谢谢
Excuse me, sir, is this your vehicle?
对不起，这是你的吗？
I'll be with you in a moment. I'll be right back.
等一下，我很快回来
Aisle or window? Smoking or non-smoking?
走廊还是窗户旁？ 吸烟还是非吸烟？
- What was the middle one? - Anything in non-smoking is fine.
- 中间的是什么？ - 只要在非吸烟区，哪里都可以
Gate 1 4 is boarding now.
14号闸现在开始登机
Rio!
里约热内卢！
Don't look back. There's a cop right behind us.
不要向后看，后面有警察
Quick.
快点
- Yes, we can just do it, Mr. Leach. - Great.
- 利奇先生，我们做到的 - 很好
Luggage?
行李？
Don't really need any.
不需要它们了
- Gate 1 4. - Thank you.
- 14号闸 - 谢谢
Come on, Archie. Pick up the phone.
阿奇，快，接电话
Wait, sir. Airport Security.
等一下，机场保安
- May I see your boarding pass, please? - Oh, yes, certainly.
- 可以看一看你的登机证吗？ - 好
Very good. Now, would you mind stepping over here please?
请你过来这一边，好吗？
- Oh, look, the Queen. - Where?
- 你看，是女皇 - 哪里？
Okay. Don't get excited.
不用紧张
Oh, it's you. I was actually worried there for a minute.
是你，我担心了好一阵子
- Keep your hands up. - No!
- 举高双手 - 不！
- Put 'em up! - I'll make a deal with you.
- 举高手 - 我跟你来个协议吧
- I'll put one up. - Put the other one up!
- 我会举高一只 - 把另一只举高
Which looks better?
哪一个看来好一点？
I'm warning you, Otto.
奥图 ，我警告你
What are you gonna do, shoot me?
你会怎样做？向我开枪？
Gun me down in cold blood like a dog?
像向狗开枪一样？
If you wanna settle something with me, then why don't you fight me?
如果你想解决，何不和我决斗？
You're a man, aren't you? Then let's fight like men. Come on!
你是男人吧？ 我们要像男人般决斗
All right.
好
- All right, then. - Okay.
- 好 - 好
- You look good, Arch. - That's right.
- 阿奇，你看起来不错 - 对
- I used to box for Oxford. - Oh, yeah?
- 我以前在牛津打拳的 - 是吗？
I used to kill for the CIA. Now, get your hands up.
我以前为中央情报局杀人 举高双手
You spineless bimbo.
你这个笨蛋
Now, out.
出去
I'm gonna have to shoot you now.
我现在要向你开枪
But I've got a little time before my plane leaves...
我在飞机起飞前有一点时间
and I'm longing to humiliate you.
我很想侮辱你
So get in that barrel.
进去那个桶子里
- What? - In the barrel.
- 什么？ - 走进桶子里
Right.
对
You English. You think you're so superior, don't you?
你们英国人自以为很优越？
Well, you're the filth of the planet.
你们是地球的垃圾
A bunch of pompous, badly dressed...
一班自大、没衣着品味...
poverty-stricken, sexually repressed...
穷困、性抑压的...
football hooligans.
足球暴徒
Good-bye, Archie.
阿奇，再见
Well, at least we're not irretrievably vulgar.
至少我们不是那么低俗
You know your problem? You don't like winners.
你知道你的问题所在吗？ 你不喜欢胜利者
- Winners? - Yeah. Winners.
- 胜利者？ - 对，胜利者
Winners, like North Vietnam?
胜利者，像北越？
Shut up!
住口
We did not lose Vietnam. It was a tie.
我们没有失去越南 那场战争平手
I'm telling ya, baby, they kicked your little ass there.
他们在那里打败你们
Boy, they whooped your hide real good.
他们彻底打败你们
- No, they didn't.
- 他们没有 - 他们有
- Yes, they did.
- 不，他们没有 - 是的，他们有
No
不， 他们...
Shut up!
住口
- Good-bye, Archie. - You gonna shoot me?
- 阿奇，再见 - 你会开枪杀我吗？
Yes, afraid so, old chap. Sorry.
我恐怕是，对不起
Look, Otto!
奥图！
Revenge!
报仇
It's Ken coming to kill me.
肯会来杀我
How are you gonna catch me, Ken?
肯，你怎样抓我？
Now, where was I? Oh, yeah.
我在哪里？
Shit! God--
糟了 ！
Fucking limey cement.
可恶的水泥
Wait!
慢着！
Kenny! May I call you Kenny?
肯尼，我可以叫你肯尼吗？
- Remember Wanda! - I've got the deal of a lifetime.
- 记住万达！ - 我们有协议的
Fifty-fifty. You and me. What do you say?
大家五五分帐，好吗？
Okay, sixty-forty.
好，六四分帐
- That's my final offer. - Revenge!
- 那是我最后的建议 - 报仇！
I've got an idea. You take it all. Yeah.
我有个主意，你拿去全部
Here's my boarding pass.
这是我的登机证
I'm gonna-- I'm gonna kill you.
我会...我会杀死你
Okay, fine. Come at me. Give me your best shot.
好，杀死我吧
Go on. You don't have the guts. Admit it.
杀吧，你没有胆量的
Okay, you have the guts. Good. Wait.
你有胆量，等一下
Death.
死亡
All right, I'm sorry I ate your fish, okay?
对不起，我吃了你的鱼 好吗？
- I'm sorry. - Revenge!
- 对不起 - 报仇！
Jesus, I said I'm sorry! What the--
天，我说了对不起！
Got him!
收拾他！
Got you again, you bastard!
收拾你，混蛋
Hey, I've lost my stutter. It's gone.
我的口吃消失了
I can speak.
我能够说话
How much wood could a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could chuck wood?
四牌楼有四辆四轮大马车
Now, listen, two things.
你听着，两件事...
One: behave yourself from now on or I'll break your neck, okay?
一，请你保持良好行为 否则我会勒死你
Two:
二
Gorbachev, Glasnost--
戈尔巴乔夫，公开地...
Molotov.
莫洛托夫
- Blinis. - Lenin.
- 俄式薄煎饼 - 列宁
Pushkin.
普希金
- Chicken Kiev. - Good.
- 基辅鸡 - 很好
Dostoyevsky.
陀思妥也夫斯基
Rubles.
卢布
Vladivostok.
符拉迪沃斯托克
Asshole!
混蛋！